<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Gabo's Teaching Portfolio - PER Review</title><link href="https://gortiz-pena.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://gortiz-pena.github.io/feeds/per-review.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://gortiz-pena.github.io/</id><updated>2019-03-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated><entry><title>Redish's Teaching and Learning Physics, Chapter 3</title><link href="https://gortiz-pena.github.io/redish-03.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-27T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-03-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Gabriel H. Ortiz-Peña</name></author><id>tag:gortiz-pena.github.io,2019-03-27:/redish-03.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the first half of a chapter on the “Hidden Curriculum” of physics courses. After discussing the cognitive model of student learning in the previous chapter, this chapter focuses on students’ model of learning and science in general, as well as their expectations of the class. This first part …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the first half of a chapter on the “Hidden Curriculum” of physics courses. After discussing the cognitive model of student learning in the previous chapter, this chapter focuses on students’ model of learning and science in general, as well as their expectations of the class. This first part is focused on expectations; specifically, it is focused on the discrepancy between the expectations of the instructor and the students. Redish describes the hidden curriculum, the expectations of most physics instructors for students to “make sense of what they are learning”, and the reasons why students fail to do this. He uses an example from Hammer (1996) to show how students may use the desired reasoning to arrive at false conclusions and how the correct conclusion is weak without the reasoning skills to defend it. Finally, the section on expectations concludes with a pessimistic discussion on how students do not relate the introductory physics curriculum to the world around them, and how that connection actually weakens after going through a physics class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does the hidden curriculum need to be hidden? I think that clarifying expectations beforehand is a general principle of building positive relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like the discussion on the hidden curriculum is based on a deficit model; could a more positive model work better to examine the mismatch in expectations? Would Hammer’s epistemic resources a good way to frame this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The failure to connect to the real world seems to me to be a result of the elicit­confront­resolve strategy to “correct” student misconceptions; do students who learn in environments that make use of their cognitive resources see more connections to their experiences outside the classroom?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry></feed>